<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chinese on North East Asia Security and International Relations</title>
    <link>https://neasair.org/categories/chinese/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chinese on North East Asia Security and International Relations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neasair.org/categories/chinese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan Affairs Office - American vessels navigating through the Taiwan Straight is sending the wrong message to Taiwan Independence advocates</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/tao-vessels-send-wrong-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/tao-vessels-send-wrong-message/</guid>
      <description>Taiwan Affairs Office: American vessels navigating through the Taiwan Straight is sending the wrong message to ‘Taiwan Independence’ [advocates] 国台办：美舰穿航台湾海峡的行为向“台独”传递错误信号 Xinhua
http://www.xinhuanet.com/2021-03/17/c_1127222759.htm March 17, 2021
Cha Wenye, Liu Huan, Chen Shu
Taiwan Affairs Office spokesperson Zhu Fenglian responded to an enquiry on March 17 by stating an American vessel’s navigation through the Taiwan Strait is sending the wrong message to ‘Taiwan independence’ separatist forces, is intentionally interfering in, and worsening the situation in, the region, and is damaging and endangering peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Taiwan Affairs Office explains the main points of the 14th Five Year Plan - We hope our Taiwanese compatriots understand it, take advantage carriers</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/tao-five-year-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/tao-five-year-plan/</guid>
      <description>The Taiwan Affairs Office explains the main points of the 14th Five Year Plan : We hope our Taiwanese compatriots understand it, take advantage 国台办解读“十四五”规划纲要：希望台胞全面了解、乘势而上 China News http://www.chinanews.com/tw/2021/03-17/9434580.shtml March 17, 2021 By Shi Longhong, Liu Huan, Chen Shu, In a regular press conference held on March 17, the Taiwan Affairs Office spokesperson Zhu Fenglian explained the parts of China’s 14th Five Year that relate to cross strait relations, saying that she hoped Taiwanese compatriots would understand all facets of the ambitious blueprint for the future development of the nation’s infrastructure that were set out in the summary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>075 Type’s 30,000 tons is enough, because China has two ‘outdated’ aircraft carriers</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/30000-tons-is-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/30000-tons-is-enough/</guid>
      <description>075 Type’s 30,000 tons is enough, because China has two ‘outdated’ aircraft carriers Updated: Jul 19, 2019
075三万吨足够了 因为中国有2艘“落后”航母FenghuangJul 8, 2019
https://mil.ifeng.com/c/7o8UAju0Ggq
Fenghuang-online Military Affairs / Fenghuang-online Military Affairs Editorial
 075三万吨足够了 因为中国有2艘“落后”航母
 Subsequent to the recent appearance on military blogs of the Type 075 Amphibious Assault Ship [more commonly known as the Type 075 landing helicopter dock], much conjecture has again emerged in relation to the “small flat platform/deck” that is second in size only to that of an aircraft carrier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Nuclear Umbrella won&#39;t make North Korea Abandon Nuclear Weapons</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-wont-abandon-nukes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-wont-abandon-nukes/</guid>
      <description>A Nuclear Umbrella won&amp;rsquo;t make North Korea Abandon Nuclear Weapons Updated: Jul 19, 2019
中国向朝鲜提供核保护劝其弃核不现实Global Times (Huanqiu)Nov 13, 2013
http://mil.huanqiu.com/paper/2013-11/4558761.html?agt=15422
Full title: It is not Realistic for China to Provide North Korea with a Nuclear Umbrella in order to Persuade it to Abandon Nuclear Weapons
Zhang Liangui 张琏瑰 - Institute for International Strategic Studies of the Central Party School of the Communist Party of China 中共中央黨校國際戰略研究所</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: If American arms sales go too far they will endanger Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/american-arms-sales-may-endanger-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/american-arms-sales-may-endanger-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>Editorial: If American arms sales go too far they will endanger Taiwan Updated: Jul 19, 2019
社评：美对台军售，走过头就是台湾之危Global TimesJuly 9, 2019
http://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1638561132431613159&amp;amp;wfr=spider&amp;amp;for=pc
America’s Department of Defence announced on Monday that it had approved the sale of military equipment worth approximately 2.2 billion American dollars to Taiwan. The deal includes 108 M1a2T Abraham tanks and 250 FIM-92 Stinger Man-Portable Air Defence Systems. Many American media reports pointed out that the sale occurred in the backdrop of the ongoing trade war between America and China.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
