<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>japan on North East Asia Security and International Relations</title>
    <link>https://neasair.org/categories/japan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in japan on North East Asia Security and International Relations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neasair.org/categories/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anti JSDF ideology is rampant in academia</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/anti-jsdf-ideology-academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/anti-jsdf-ideology-academia/</guid>
      <description>‘Anti JSDF ideology’ is rampant in academia: Overcome the division between defence and science and technology! In 10 years time China’s strength will be overwhelming; whoever loses the battle of science and technology loses the war.
学術界にはびこる「反自衛隊イデオロギー」　科学技術と国防の分断を克服せよ！　 １０年後の中国の力は圧倒的に、戦争では科学技術で負ける方が負ける https://news.yahoo.co.jp/articles/26000ba3d34816afde9824446a86358f346b3f4e
March 17, 2021
Kanehara Nobukatsu (Former chief of Japan’s Ministry of Foreign Affair’s North American Affairs Bureau U.S.-Japan Security Treaty division, former head of the International Legal Affairs Bureau, former Director of General Affairs of Department of the Foreign Policy Bureau).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Heisei to the Reiwa era - the Self Defence Force and National Security of a Changing Japan</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/the-sdf-and-national-security-of-a-changing-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/the-sdf-and-national-security-of-a-changing-japan/</guid>
      <description>From the Heisei to the Reiwa era - the Self Defence Force and National Security of a Changing Japan Updated: Jul 19, 2019
平成から令和へ。変わる日本の自衛隊と安全保障 Asahi May 22, 2019
https://webronza.asahi.com/politics/articles/2019052200004.html
Gen Nakatani, Former Minister of Defence, on the transformation of the JSDF (Japanese Self Defence Force) and national security*, and the current state of Japan.
Gen Nakatani - Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) Member of the House of Representatives, Former Minister of Defence</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Abe administration&#39;s diplomatic achievements are being called into question [excerpt]</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/abe-administration-achievements-called-into-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/abe-administration-achievements-called-into-question/</guid>
      <description>The Abe administration&amp;rsquo;s diplomatic achievements are being called into question [excerpt] Updated: Jul 13, 2019
北方領土、拉致解決進まず＝日中改善も公船侵入続く－問われる安倍政権【19参院選】 Jiji, July 2, 2019
https://www.jiji.com/jc/article?k=2019070200701&amp;amp;g=pol
Full title: No progress in resolving the Northern Territories / kidnapping [disputes] = In spite of improvements in Sino-Japanese relations, Chinese public vessels continuously encroach in Japanese waters - Abe’s administration is being called into question (19 House of Councillors election)
 北方領土、拉致解決進まず＝日中改善も公船侵入続く－問われる安倍政権【19参院選】
 In the Liberal Democratic Party’s (LDP) campaign promises during the upper house elections, diplomacy was thrust to the forefront.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘The security treaty between the United States and Japan is unfair’ is an old argument</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/us-japan-security-treaty-an-old-argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/us-japan-security-treaty-an-old-argument/</guid>
      <description>‘The security treaty between the United States and Japan is unfair’ is an old argument Updated: Jul 13, 2019
  「日米安保は不公平」は、今に始まった議論ではない Asabi Shimbun Globe July 7, 2019
https://globe.asahi.com/article/12508614
Since it was reported that President Trump talked about ‘tearing up’ the Japan-U.S. security treaty, there has been ongoing uncertainty has about what will become of the Japan-U.S. alliance. Although it doesn’t appear to be the case that this was directly touched upon in the leaders’ meeting, it is clear that a conflict of interests exists.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
