<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>korean on North East Asia Security and International Relations</title>
    <link>http://neasair.org/categories/korean/</link>
    <description>Recent content in korean on North East Asia Security and International Relations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://neasair.org/categories/korean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Anti-China sentiments are spreading in Pyongyang</title>
      <link>http://neasair.org/blog/2019/pyongyang-anti-china-sentiment-spreading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://neasair.org/blog/2019/pyongyang-anti-china-sentiment-spreading/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 19, 2019
평양시민들 사이에 반중 분위기 확산
RFA, Aug. 22, 2018
https://www.rfa.org/korean/in_focus/nk_nuclear_talks/antichina-08222018102647.html
Anchor:
Leading up to the 70th anniversary of the political leadership of the Worker’s Party of Korea’s (WPK), a rumour has spread in Pynogyang that China’s Chairman Xi Jinping could visit North Korea. However, a source has indicated that anti-China sentiments have grown among Pyongyang intellectuals as well as among the city’s residents.
 평양시민들 사이에 반중 분위기 확산</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Korea, which is calling for self-rejuvination, is preparing itself for the global economy</title>
      <link>http://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-preparing-for-global-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-preparing-for-global-economy/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 13, 2019
자력갱생 외치는 북한, 글로벌경제 대비
Yonhap News TV
June 8, 2019
http://www.yonhapnewstv.co.kr/MYH20190607019400038/?did=1825m
(Anchor) Although North Korea is calling for economic construction through self-rejunivation*, internally, Pyongyang is emphasising the concept of globalisation and is attempting to transition its economy.
 자력갱생 외치는 북한, 글로벌경제 대비
 Kim Jung-un, chairman of North Korea’s state affairs commission, has personally come out and tried to raise awareness about intellectual property rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>President Moon warns Japan: ‘A necessary response when Korean companies are harmed’</title>
      <link>http://neasair.org/blog/2019/moon-warns-japan-when-korean-companies-harmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://neasair.org/blog/2019/moon-warns-japan-when-korean-companies-harmed/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 13, 2019
문 대통령 “한국기업 피해 땐 필요한 대응” 일본에 경고
Hani.co.kr, July 8, 2019
http://www.hani.co.kr/arti/politics/bluehouse/900913.html#csidx6183caecd1c96ed8c3be1b3174e758f
In response to restrictions on the export of core materials for semi-conductors and display devises being led by Japan’s Prime Minister Shinzo Abe, President Moon Jae-in on Jul 8 warned that ‘the vicious cycle of response and recrimination is definitely not what either nation wants,’ yet ‘if damage to Korean companies actually occurs, as the representative government we will have to respond.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
