<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>korean on North East Asia Security and International Relations</title>
    <link>https://neasair.org/categories/korean/</link>
    <description>Recent content in korean on North East Asia Security and International Relations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neasair.org/categories/korean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>China and North Korea’s friendship will ‘rupture’ in the event of a North Korean provocation</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/sino-north-relationship-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/sino-north-relationship-change/</guid>
      <description>China and North Korea’s friendship will ‘rupture’ in the event of a North Korean provocation/a change in the relationship between North Korea and America 북중 우호, 北 도발·북미관계 변화 시 &amp;lsquo;균열&amp;rsquo; NewsIs [Translation/paraphrase]
July 7, 2021 https://newsis.com/view/?id=NISX20210701_0001497770&amp;amp;cID=10301&amp;amp;pID=10300
Daero Park
북한과 중국이 연일 우호 관계를 과시하고 있지만 북한이 고강도 군사 도발을 감행하거나 북미 관계가 변화할 경우 양측 간 균열이 발생할 가능성을 배제할 수 없다는 지적이 나온다.
North Korea and China often put their friendship on display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sino-North Korea relations are now heading towards a ‘post Corona’ era</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/sino-north-post-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/sino-north-post-corona/</guid>
      <description>Sino-North Korea relations are now heading towards a ‘post Corona’ era [김황록 칼럼] 지금 북중관계는 &amp;lsquo;포스트 코로나&amp;rsquo; 시대로 향하고 있다 News Prime
March 7, 2021 http://www.newsprime.co.kr/news/article/?no=535831
Kim Hwang-rok, former head of the Defense Intelligence Agency
In mid February, while North Korea was still beset with the ‘triple hardships’ of international sanctions, the Corona virus and natural disasters, its Foreign Ministry announced that its ambassador to China, Ji Jae-ryong (74), would be replaced by Lee Yong-nam (61).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defence Whitepaper: Comparing “the Military Strength of North and South Korea”</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/2020-korean-defence-whitepaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/2020-korean-defence-whitepaper/</guid>
      <description>Defence Whitepaper: Comparing “the Military Strength of North and South Korea” 국방백서 ‘남북 군사력’ 비교해보니 http://asiae.co.kr/,
February 2, 2021 https://www.asiae.co.kr/article/2021020210290036598
Asia Business Daily Military Affairs Reporter Yang Nak-kyu:
The standing army (defence force personnel minus non-serving reserves) of the North Korean military (the Korean People’s Army’s = KPA) is 2.3 times larger than South Korea’s (ROK), and it is estimated that the North also comes out on top in terms of its number of tanks, fighter jets and naval vessels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-China sentiments are spreading in Pyongyang</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/pyongyang-anti-china-sentiment-spreading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/pyongyang-anti-china-sentiment-spreading/</guid>
      <description>Anti-China sentiments are spreading in Pyongyang Updated: Jul 19, 2019
  평양시민들 사이에 반중 분위기 확산 RFA Aug. 22, 2018
https://www.rfa.org/korean/in_focus/nk_nuclear_talks/antichina-08222018102647.html
Anchor:
Leading up to the 70th anniversary of the political leadership of the Worker’s Party of Korea’s (WPK), a rumour has spread in Pynogyang that China’s Chairman Xi Jinping could visit North Korea. However, a source has indicated that anti-China sentiments have grown among Pyongyang intellectuals as well as among the city’s residents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Korea, which is calling for self-rejuvination, is preparing itself for the global economy</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-preparing-for-global-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-preparing-for-global-economy/</guid>
      <description>North Korea, which is calling for self-rejuvination, is preparing itself for the global economy Updated: Jul 13, 2019
  자력갱생 외치는 북한, 글로벌경제 대비 Yonhap News TV June 8, 2019
http://www.yonhapnewstv.co.kr/MYH20190607019400038/?did=1825m
(Anchor) Although North Korea is calling for economic construction through self-rejunivation*, internally, Pyongyang is emphasising the concept of globalisation and is attempting to transition its economy.
 자력갱생 외치는 북한, 글로벌경제 대비
 Kim Jung-un, chairman of North Korea’s state affairs commission, has personally come out and tried to raise awareness about intellectual property rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>President Moon warns Japan: ‘A necessary response when Korean companies are harmed’</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/moon-warns-japan-when-korean-companies-harmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/moon-warns-japan-when-korean-companies-harmed/</guid>
      <description>President Moon warns Japan: ‘A necessary response when Korean companies are harmed’ Updated: Jul 13, 2019
문 대통령 “한국기업 피해 땐 필요한 대응” 일본에 경고 Hani.co.kr, July 8, 2019
http://www.hani.co.kr/arti/politics/bluehouse/900913.html#csidx6183caecd1c96ed8c3be1b3174e758f
In response to restrictions on the export of core materials for semi-conductors and display devises being led by Japan’s Prime Minister Shinzo Abe, President Moon Jae-in on Jul 8 warned that ‘the vicious cycle of response and recrimination is definitely not what either nation wants,’ yet ‘if damage to Korean companies actually occurs, as the representative government we will have to respond.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
