<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scholar on North East Asia Security and International Relations</title>
    <link>https://neasair.org/categories/scholar/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scholar on North East Asia Security and International Relations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neasair.org/categories/scholar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: If American arms sales go too far they will endanger Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/american-arms-sales-may-endanger-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/american-arms-sales-may-endanger-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>Editorial: If American arms sales go too far they will endanger Taiwan Updated: Jul 19, 2019
社评：美对台军售，走过头就是台湾之危Global TimesJuly 9, 2019
http://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1638561132431613159&amp;amp;wfr=spider&amp;amp;for=pc
America’s Department of Defence announced on Monday that it had approved the sale of military equipment worth approximately 2.2 billion American dollars to Taiwan. The deal includes 108 M1a2T Abraham tanks and 250 FIM-92 Stinger Man-Portable Air Defence Systems. Many American media reports pointed out that the sale occurred in the backdrop of the ongoing trade war between America and China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Korean War and China’s Strategic Decisions</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/korean-war-china-strategic-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/korean-war-china-strategic-decisions/</guid>
      <description>The Korean War and China’s Strategic Decisions 朝顯戰爭與中國的決策Shen Zhihua 沈志華Notes from Shen Zhihua&amp;rsquo;s presentation, delivered at the Yonsei Institute of Sinology (Seoul), Jun 19, 2019
Periodization of the Korean war (in terms of shifts in China’s strategic aims):
 朝顯戰爭與中國的決策
   Engaging in military action to pursue a settlement - October 1950 to December 1950
  Fighting without negotiation: Pushing the American military back to the Pacific Ocean - January 1951 to May 1951.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
