<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>North East Asia Security and International Relations</title>
    <link>https://neasair.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on North East Asia Security and International Relations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://neasair.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What happened in Hong Kong</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2022/what-happened-in-hong-kong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2022/what-happened-in-hong-kong/</guid>
      <description>TRANSLATOR&amp;rsquo;S NOTE:
This is an excerpt from my draft translation of &amp;ldquo;What happened in Hong Kong?&amp;rdquo; (2021) - a widely shared, free
Chinese language ebook that was compiled by a group of anonymous authors affiliated with Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s pro-democracy
movement. The book discusses the history of the 2019 Anti-extradition Movement, including its causes, constitution, key
events/milestones, and legacy. While it presents an informed and well structured account of this important part of</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>China and North Korea’s friendship will ‘rupture’ in the event of a North Korean provocation</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/sino-north-relationship-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/sino-north-relationship-change/</guid>
      <description>China and North Korea’s friendship will ‘rupture’ in the event of a North Korean provocation/a change in the relationship between North Korea and America 북중 우호, 北 도발·북미관계 변화 시 &amp;lsquo;균열&amp;rsquo; NewsIs [Translation/paraphrase]
July 7, 2021 https://newsis.com/view/?id=NISX20210701_0001497770&amp;amp;cID=10301&amp;amp;pID=10300
Daero Park
북한과 중국이 연일 우호 관계를 과시하고 있지만 북한이 고강도 군사 도발을 감행하거나 북미 관계가 변화할 경우 양측 간 균열이 발생할 가능성을 배제할 수 없다는 지적이 나온다.
North Korea and China often put their friendship on display.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Wrap March 27 (update April 2)</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/media-wrap-april/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/media-wrap-april/</guid>
      <description>Media Wrap-up Late March (April 2 update)   North Korea&amp;rsquo;s guided missile launch: did China already know? &amp;ldquo;北 탄도미사일 발사 &amp;lsquo;중국은 미리 알았을까?&amp;rdquo;
https://www.news1.kr/articles/?4254857
March 27, 2021.
  China on the possibility of a meeting between China and South Korea&amp;rsquo;s foreign ministers: &amp;ldquo;You are welcome to visit China whenever you like&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;중국, 한중 외교장관 회담 가능성에 &amp;ldquo;편한 시간 방문 환영&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; https://www.yna.co.kr/view/AKR20210326148200083?input=1195m March 26, 2021.
  Aiming to strengthen relations with Taiwan, members of the Liberal Democratic Party adopt a resolution to enact the Japan-Taiwan Exchange Basic Law</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why did Taiwan’s airforce urgently announce it had resumed flying?</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/taiwan-air-force-overstretched/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/taiwan-air-force-overstretched/</guid>
      <description>Why did Taiwan’s airforce urgently announce it had resumed flying? Expert: Taiwan’s air force personnel are already overstretched 台空军为何急着宣布复飞？专家：台军航空兵兵力已捉襟见肘 https://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1695792677792730501&amp;amp;wfr=spider&amp;amp;for=pc
Global Times
April 1, 2021
Taiwanese air force planes ceased flying across the board after two Taiwanese F-5E fighters collided and crashed. According to a report in Taiwan’s Central News Agency (CNA) on March 30, Taiwan announced on that day that other than its F-5E’s, most of its fighters would resume flying before the end of March.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>America’s collapsing supremacy in East Asia</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/americas-collapsing-supremacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/americas-collapsing-supremacy/</guid>
      <description>America’s collapsing supremacy in East Asia: Wary of a crises in the Taiwan Strait, entering into a new phase in dealing with China.
東アジアで崩れる米優位　台湾有事警戒、対中新局面 https://www.nikkei.com/article/DGXZQODE25326025032021000000/?unlock=1
Nikkei
March 29, 2021
&amp;lsquo;5 years of implementing the National Security Legislation&amp;rsquo; (Part 1)
March 29 marked 5 years since the implementation of the National Security Legislation. This deepened the Japan-U.S. alliance by making it possible to execute, within limitations, the right to collective self-defence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Wrap March</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/media-wrap-march/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/media-wrap-march/</guid>
      <description>Media Wrap-up March (headlines)   A year of severed trade between North Korean and China&amp;hellip; we need to prepare for a change in North Korea’s foreign relations &amp;ldquo;북·중 교역 단절 1년&amp;hellip;北 대외관계 전환 대비해야&amp;rdquo;
http://www.newspim.com/news/view/20210316001149
March 17, 2021.
  Even Xi Jinping is afraid: Furious Japan and America fire off a ‘terrible blow’ towards the Senkaku Island-coveting China 習近平も恐怖する…尖閣を狙う中国に、マジギレの日米が放つ「凄まじい一撃」
https://gendai.ismedia.jp/articles/-/81341
March 19, 2021
  Wang Yi on the South China Sea：rule out interference, promote consultation on ‘standards for behaviour in the South China sea’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti JSDF ideology is rampant in academia</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/anti-jsdf-ideology-academia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/anti-jsdf-ideology-academia/</guid>
      <description>‘Anti JSDF ideology’ is rampant in academia: Overcome the division between defence and science and technology! In 10 years time China’s strength will be overwhelming; whoever loses the battle of science and technology loses the war.
学術界にはびこる「反自衛隊イデオロギー」　科学技術と国防の分断を克服せよ！　 １０年後の中国の力は圧倒的に、戦争では科学技術で負ける方が負ける https://news.yahoo.co.jp/articles/26000ba3d34816afde9824446a86358f346b3f4e
March 17, 2021
Kanehara Nobukatsu (Former chief of Japan’s Ministry of Foreign Affair’s North American Affairs Bureau U.S.-Japan Security Treaty division, former head of the International Legal Affairs Bureau, former Director of General Affairs of Department of the Foreign Policy Bureau).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan Affairs Office - American vessels navigating through the Taiwan Straight is sending the wrong message to Taiwan Independence advocates</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/tao-vessels-send-wrong-message/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/tao-vessels-send-wrong-message/</guid>
      <description>Taiwan Affairs Office: American vessels navigating through the Taiwan Straight is sending the wrong message to ‘Taiwan Independence’ [advocates] 国台办：美舰穿航台湾海峡的行为向“台独”传递错误信号 Xinhua
http://www.xinhuanet.com/2021-03/17/c_1127222759.htm
March 17, 2021
By Cha Wenye, Liu Huan, Chen Shu
Taiwan Affairs Office spokesperson Zhu Fenglian responded to an enquiry on March 17 by stating an American vessel’s navigation through the Taiwan Strait is sending the wrong message to ‘Taiwan independence’ separatist forces, is intentionally interfering in, and worsening the situation in, the region, and is damaging and endangering peace and stability across the Taiwan Strait.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Taiwan Affairs Office explains the main points of the 14th Five Year Plan - We hope our Taiwanese compatriots understand it, take advantage carriers</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/tao-five-year-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/tao-five-year-plan/</guid>
      <description>The Taiwan Affairs Office explains the main points of the 14th Five Year Plan : We hope our Taiwanese compatriots understand it, take advantage 国台办解读“十四五”规划纲要：希望台胞全面了解、乘势而上 China News
http://www.chinanews.com/tw/2021/03-17/9434580.shtml
March 17, 2021
By Shi Longhong, Liu Huan, Chen Shu
In a regular press conference held on March 17, the Taiwan Affairs Office spokesperson Zhu Fenglian explained the parts of China’s 14th Five Year that relate to cross strait relations, saying that she hoped Taiwanese compatriots would understand all facets of the ambitious blueprint for the future development of the nation’s infrastructure that were set out in the summary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 19:05:24 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>Email: corey@neasair.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Taiwan Really Buying the ‘Wrong’ Weapons?</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/is-taiwan-buying-wrong-weapons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/is-taiwan-buying-wrong-weapons/</guid>
      <description>Is Taiwan Really Buying the ‘Wrong’ Weapons? The Diplomat March 31, 2020
https://thediplomat.com/2020/03/is-taiwan-really-buying-the-wrong-weapons/
Few were surprised when Taiwan’s presidential election resulted in the return of the America-friendly Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) candidate Tsai Ing-wen this January. As expected, Tsai’s tough stand on the issue of Taiwanese sovereignty was a winner, with the Hong Kong extradition protests serving as a timely warning of the dangers of the “one country two systems” model Beijing wants to impose on Taiwan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sino-North Korea relations are now heading towards a ‘post Corona’ era</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/sino-north-post-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/sino-north-post-corona/</guid>
      <description>Sino-North Korea relations are now heading towards a ‘post Corona’ era [김황록 칼럼] 지금 북중관계는 &amp;lsquo;포스트 코로나&amp;rsquo; 시대로 향하고 있다 News Prime
March 7, 2021 http://www.newsprime.co.kr/news/article/?no=535831
Kim Hwang-rok, former head of the Defense Intelligence Agency
In mid February, while North Korea was still beset with the ‘triple hardships’ of international sanctions, the Corona virus and natural disasters, its Foreign Ministry announced that its ambassador to China, Ji Jae-ryong (74), would be replaced by Lee Yong-nam (61).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan’s cabinet reshuffle a response to China’s ‘unrestricted warfare’</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/taiwans-cabinet-reshuffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/taiwans-cabinet-reshuffle/</guid>
      <description>Taiwan’s cabinet reshuffle a response to China’s ‘unrestricted warfare’ The Strategist 12 Mar 2021
https://www.aspistrategist.org.au/taiwans-cabinet-reshuffle-a-response-to-chinas-unrestricted-warfare/
Last month, Taiwan’s government announced several personnel changes in leadership positions in its defence and security team, including the key posts of defence minister and National Security Bureau director.
While at least one of these changes had been months in the making, the fact that several occurred concurrently, and were announced just after the Chinese New Year break, has prompted conjecture that certain recent developments have prompted a shift in the island’s strategic thinking&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>한국 현대사  South Korean Contemporary History - A New Milestone</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/contemporary-korean-history-book-translation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/contemporary-korean-history-book-translation/</guid>
      <description>한국 현대사 South Korean Contemporary History - A New Milestone (Part 1) Seo Joong-Seok 2020
http://www.kyobobook.co.kr/product/detailViewKor.laf?mallGb=KOR&amp;amp;ejkGb=KOR&amp;amp;linkClass=190917&amp;amp;barcode=9788901241630
A New Milestone On October 27 1979, the day after Park Chung-hee was killed, it was declared that the entire nation with the exception of Jeju island would be under a state of emergency. On that same day the Prime Minister Choi Kyu-hah became the acting president. High ranking military officials held a meeting over October 29 and 30 and agreed to abolish the Yushin reforms, and on November 10 Acting President Choi, in compliance with the Yushin constitution, was elected to be the new President.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defence Whitepaper: Comparing “the Military Strength of North and South Korea”</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/2020-korean-defence-whitepaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2021/2020-korean-defence-whitepaper/</guid>
      <description>Defence Whitepaper: Comparing “the Military Strength of North and South Korea” 국방백서 ‘남북 군사력’ 비교해보니 http://asiae.co.kr/,
February 2, 2021 https://www.asiae.co.kr/article/2021020210290036598
Asia Business Daily Military Affairs Reporter Yang Nak-kyu:
The standing army (defence force personnel minus non-serving reserves) of the North Korean military (the Korean People’s Army’s = KPA) is 2.3 times larger than South Korea’s (ROK), and it is estimated that the North also comes out on top in terms of its number of tanks, fighter jets and naval vessels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leave Donald Trump&#39;s triumphant Taiwan policy alone</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/trumps-triumphant-taiwan-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/trumps-triumphant-taiwan-policy/</guid>
      <description>Leave Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s triumphant Taiwan policy alone Yazhou Zhoukan December 12, 2020
https://nationalinterest.org/feature/leave-donald-trump%E2%80%99s-triumphant-taiwan-policy-alone-174298
Patrick Mendis, Corey Lee Bell
Joe Biden should follow the course set by Donald Trump; there should be no U-turn based on naive hopes that goodwill can temper President Xi Jinping’s growing and increasingly impatient desire to pressure Taiwan into capitulation&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE 2020 YUSHAN FORUM: CAN TAIWAN BECOME A “REGIONAL RESILIENCE HUB”?</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/2020-yushan-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/2020-yushan-forum/</guid>
      <description>THE 2020 YUSHAN FORUM: CAN TAIWAN BECOME A “REGIONAL RESILIENCE HUB”? Taiwan Insight October 22, 2020
https://taiwaninsight.org/2020/10/22/the-2020-yushan-forum-can-taiwan-become-a-regional-resilience-hub/
The annual Yushan Forum was inaugurated in 2017, yet has quickly come to assume the mantle of one of Taiwan’s leading non-governmental platforms for international dialogue. Its 2020 incarnation was no different, and featured keynote speeches from influential political figures including President Tsai Ing-Wen, Australia’s former Prime Minister Malcolm Turnbull, and Sweden’s former Prime Minister Carl Bildt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qiao Liang: The Taiwan problem puts at stake the fate of the nation</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/qiao-liang-on-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/qiao-liang-on-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>Qiao Liang: The Taiwan problem puts at stake the fate of the nation, we can’t afford undue haste 乔良：台湾问题攸关国运不可轻率急进 US-CHina Perception Monitor May 4, 2020
https://www.uscnpm.com/model_item.html?action=view&amp;amp;table=article&amp;amp;id=21580
[Note: On May 3 the US-China Perception Monitor re-posted retired major-general Qiao Liang’s interview for the Chinese language Bauhinia Magazine (2020, Issue 5), which was titled “We shouldn’t dance to America’s tune.” The re-post featured a discussion on the interview which was penned by a reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taiwan&#39;s defence quandary - American ally or protectorate?</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/taiwans-defence-quandary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/taiwans-defence-quandary/</guid>
      <description>Taiwan&amp;rsquo;s defence quandary - American ally or protectorate? Taiwan Insight April 21, 2020
https://taiwaninsight.org/2020/04/23/taiwans-defence-quandary-american-ally-or-protectorate/
The Overall Defence Concept (OCD), which was first outlined in 2017 by Taiwan’s revered former Chief of General Staff, Admiral Lee Hsi-ming, represented a paradigmatic shift in Taiwan’s approach to its defence. Many foreign analysts felt it marked a watershed moment in which the island’s leaders had finally cast aside national pride, and embraced an approach to Taiwan’s defence that belatedly acknowledged what they had been saying for years – that the balance of power across the Taiwan Strait had well and truly shifted in China’s favour&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>THE 2020 TAIWAN PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION – SOUTH KOREAN MEDIA COVERAGE WRAP UP</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/taiwans-defence-quandary/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2020/taiwans-defence-quandary/</guid>
      <description>THE 2020 TAIWAN PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION – SOUTH KOREAN MEDIA COVERAGE WRAP UP Taiwan Insight January 22, 2020
https://taiwaninsight.org/2020/01/22/the-2020-taiwan-presidential-election-south-korean-media-coverage-wrap-up/
Taiwan’s presidential elections often attract extensive media coverage in South Korea. On account of the growing volume of economic and people-to-people interaction between Taiwan and South Korea, as well as marked historical, demographic and cultural proximities between these two former Japanese colonies, many of the reports and analyses on Taiwan’s elections emanating from South Korea’s media are insightful, well informed, and arguably more multifarious in content than is the case in Western media sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WHY TAIWAN’S NEW SOUTHBOUND POLICY SHOULD STEER CLEAR OF AMERICAN GEOPOLITIK</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/nsp-steer-clear-geopolitik/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/nsp-steer-clear-geopolitik/</guid>
      <description>WHY TAIWAN’S NEW SOUTHBOUND POLICY SHOULD STEER CLEAR OF AMERICAN GEOPOLITIK Taiwan Insight November 27, 2019
https://2019/11/27/why-taiwans-new-southbound-policy-should-steer-clear-of-american-geopolitik/
The 2019 Yushan Forum, hosted by the Taiwan-Asia Exchange Foundation, lived up to its hype as a major forum on Asian trade and regional integration. In a major coup, this year’s programme succeeded in attracting a number of prominent speakers, including Taiwan’s President Tsai Ing-wen, who delivered the event’s opening address, her Vice President Chen Chien-jen, India’s former foreign secretary Shivshankar Menon, and Sandra Oudkirk, the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>朝鮮核武威懾中朝關係</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/nk-sino-chinese-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/nk-sino-chinese-article/</guid>
      <description>Is North Korea Exerting ‘Asymmetric Leverage’ Over China? Yazhou Zhoukan February 18, 2019
https://www.yzzk.com/article/details/%E6%96%B0%E6%80%9D%E7%B6%AD%E5%8F%8A%E5%85%B6%E4%BB%96%E5%B0%88%E6%AC%84/2019-07/1550115912400/%E6%9C%9D%E9%AE%AE%E6%A0%B8%E6%AD%A6%E5%A8%81%E6%87%BE%E4%B8%AD%E6%9C%9D%E9%97%9C%E4%BF%82/%E5%90%8D%E5%AE%B6%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2/%E9%8D%BE%E5%8F%AF%E5%8A%9B
近年來中朝關係屢經波折，尤其自二零一六年起，波動更為顯著。朝鮮自二零一六年初期進行數次核武和導彈試驗觸怒了北京， 導致中國罕見地支持聯合國對朝鮮實施制裁，使兩國關係陷入了新低谷。不過，從二零一八年三月起，一系列「習金會」以隆重的 規格召開，帶動中國大幅度增加了與朝鮮政府各階層的合作計劃和對朝經濟支援。此發展與許多分析家所提出的中朝「唇齒相依」 的特殊關係已不存在之說略顯不符。為什麼會這樣？&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>075 Type’s 30,000 tons is enough, because China has two ‘outdated’ aircraft carriers</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/30000-tons-is-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/30000-tons-is-enough/</guid>
      <description>075 Type’s 30,000 tons is enough, because China has two ‘outdated’ aircraft carriers Updated: Jul 19, 2019
075三万吨足够了 因为中国有2艘“落后”航母FenghuangJul 8, 2019
https://mil.ifeng.com/c/7o8UAju0Ggq
Fenghuang-online Military Affairs / Fenghuang-online Military Affairs Editorial
 075三万吨足够了 因为中国有2艘“落后”航母
 Subsequent to the recent appearance on military blogs of the Type 075 Amphibious Assault Ship [more commonly known as the Type 075 landing helicopter dock], much conjecture has again emerged in relation to the “small flat platform/deck” that is second in size only to that of an aircraft carrier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Nuclear Umbrella won&#39;t make North Korea Abandon Nuclear Weapons</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-wont-abandon-nukes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-wont-abandon-nukes/</guid>
      <description>A Nuclear Umbrella won&amp;rsquo;t make North Korea Abandon Nuclear Weapons Updated: Jul 19, 2019
中国向朝鲜提供核保护劝其弃核不现实Global Times (Huanqiu)Nov 13, 2013
http://mil.huanqiu.com/paper/2013-11/4558761.html?agt=15422
Full title: It is not Realistic for China to Provide North Korea with a Nuclear Umbrella in order to Persuade it to Abandon Nuclear Weapons
Zhang Liangui 张琏瑰 - Institute for International Strategic Studies of the Central Party School of the Communist Party of China 中共中央黨校國際戰略研究所</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: If American arms sales go too far they will endanger Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/american-arms-sales-may-endanger-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/american-arms-sales-may-endanger-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>Editorial: If American arms sales go too far they will endanger Taiwan Updated: Jul 19, 2019
社评：美对台军售，走过头就是台湾之危Global TimesJuly 9, 2019
http://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1638561132431613159&amp;amp;wfr=spider&amp;amp;for=pc
America’s Department of Defence announced on Monday that it had approved the sale of military equipment worth approximately 2.2 billion American dollars to Taiwan. The deal includes 108 M1a2T Abraham tanks and 250 FIM-92 Stinger Man-Portable Air Defence Systems. Many American media reports pointed out that the sale occurred in the backdrop of the ongoing trade war between America and China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Korean War and China’s Strategic Decisions</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/korean-war-china-strategic-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/korean-war-china-strategic-decisions/</guid>
      <description>The Korean War and China’s Strategic Decisions 朝顯戰爭與中國的決策Shen Zhihua 沈志華Notes from Shen Zhihua&amp;rsquo;s presentation, delivered at the Yonsei Institute of Sinology (Seoul), Jun 19, 2019
Periodization of the Korean war (in terms of shifts in China’s strategic aims):
 朝顯戰爭與中國的決策
   Engaging in military action to pursue a settlement - October 1950 to December 1950
  Fighting without negotiation: Pushing the American military back to the Pacific Ocean - January 1951 to May 1951.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-China sentiments are spreading in Pyongyang</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/pyongyang-anti-china-sentiment-spreading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/pyongyang-anti-china-sentiment-spreading/</guid>
      <description>Anti-China sentiments are spreading in Pyongyang Updated: Jul 19, 2019
평양시민들 사이에 반중 분위기 확산RFAAug. 22, 2018
https://www.rfa.org/korean/in_focus/nk_nuclear_talks/antichina-08222018102647.html
Anchor:
Leading up to the 70th anniversary of the political leadership of the Worker’s Party of Korea’s (WPK), a rumour has spread in Pynogyang that China’s Chairman Xi Jinping could visit North Korea. However, a source has indicated that anti-China sentiments have grown among Pyongyang intellectuals as well as among the city’s residents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Heisei to the Reiwa era - the Self Defence Force and National Security of a Changing Japan</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/the-sdf-and-national-security-of-a-changing-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/the-sdf-and-national-security-of-a-changing-japan/</guid>
      <description>From the Heisei to the Reiwa era - the Self Defence Force and National Security of a Changing Japan Updated: Jul 19, 2019
平成から令和へ。変わる日本の自衛隊と安全保障 Asahi May 22, 2019
https://webronza.asahi.com/politics/articles/2019052200004.html
Gen Nakatani, Former Minister of Defence, on the transformation of the JSDF (Japanese Self Defence Force) and national security*, and the current state of Japan.
Gen Nakatani - Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) Member of the House of Representatives, Former Minister of Defence</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Korea, which is calling for self-rejuvination, is preparing itself for the global economy</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-preparing-for-global-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/north-korea-preparing-for-global-economy/</guid>
      <description>North Korea, which is calling for self-rejuvination, is preparing itself for the global economy Updated: Jul 13, 2019
자력갱생 외치는 북한, 글로벌경제 대비Yonhap News TVJune 8, 2019
http://www.yonhapnewstv.co.kr/MYH20190607019400038/?did=1825m
(Anchor) Although North Korea is calling for economic construction through self-rejunivation*, internally, Pyongyang is emphasising the concept of globalisation and is attempting to transition its economy.
 자력갱생 외치는 북한, 글로벌경제 대비
 Kim Jung-un, chairman of North Korea’s state affairs commission, has personally come out and tried to raise awareness about intellectual property rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>President Moon warns Japan: ‘A necessary response when Korean companies are harmed’</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/moon-warns-japan-when-korean-companies-harmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/moon-warns-japan-when-korean-companies-harmed/</guid>
      <description>President Moon warns Japan: ‘A necessary response when Korean companies are harmed’ Updated: Jul 13, 2019
문 대통령 “한국기업 피해 땐 필요한 대응” 일본에 경고 Hani.co.kr, July 8, 2019
http://www.hani.co.kr/arti/politics/bluehouse/900913.html#csidx6183caecd1c96ed8c3be1b3174e758f
In response to restrictions on the export of core materials for semi-conductors and display devises being led by Japan’s Prime Minister Shinzo Abe, President Moon Jae-in on Jul 8 warned that ‘the vicious cycle of response and recrimination is definitely not what either nation wants,’ yet ‘if damage to Korean companies actually occurs, as the representative government we will have to respond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Abe administration&#39;s diplomatic achievements are being called into question [excerpt]</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/abe-administration-achievements-called-into-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/abe-administration-achievements-called-into-question/</guid>
      <description>The Abe administration&amp;rsquo;s diplomatic achievements are being called into question [excerpt] Updated: Jul 13, 2019
北方領土、拉致解決進まず＝日中改善も公船侵入続く－問われる安倍政権【19参院選】 Jiji, July 2, 2019
https://www.jiji.com/jc/article?k=2019070200701&amp;amp;g=pol
Full title: No progress in resolving the Northern Territories / kidnapping [disputes] = In spite of improvements in Sino-Japanese relations, Chinese public vessels continuously encroach in Japanese waters - Abe’s administration is being called into question (19 House of Councillors election)
 北方領土、拉致解決進まず＝日中改善も公船侵入続く－問われる安倍政権【19参院選】
 In the Liberal Democratic Party’s (LDP) campaign promises during the upper house elections, diplomacy was thrust to the forefront.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘The security treaty between the United States and Japan is unfair’ is an old argument</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/us-japan-security-treaty-an-old-argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2019/us-japan-security-treaty-an-old-argument/</guid>
      <description>‘The security treaty between the United States and Japan is unfair’ is an old argument Updated: Jul 13, 2019
「日米安保は不公平」は、今に始まった議論ではないAsabi Shimbun GlobeJuly 7, 2019
https://globe.asahi.com/article/12508614
Since it was reported that President Trump talked about ‘tearing up’ the Japan-U.S. security treaty, there has been ongoing uncertainty has about what will become of the Japan-U.S. alliance. Although it doesn’t appear to be the case that this was directly touched upon in the leaders’ meeting, it is clear that a conflict of interests exists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:09:28 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/about/</guid>
      <description>NEASAIR provides Anglophone readers interested in security issues and international relations in North East Asia with a window into the unique perspectives, insights and foci of Chinese, Japanese and Korean language media and analyses.
NEASAIR is different. Its primary aim is to give Anglophone readers interested in security and international relations in North East Asia a window into the unique perspectives, insights and foci that can be found in Chinese, Japanese and Korean language media and analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is North Korea Exerting ‘Asymmetric Leverage’ Over China?</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2018/nk-sino-relations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2018/nk-sino-relations/</guid>
      <description>Is North Korea Exerting ‘Asymmetric Leverage’ Over China? The Diplomat December 03, 2018
https://thediplomat.com/2018/12/is-north-korea-exerting-asymmetric-leverage-over-china/
The last few years have witnessed dramatic oscillations in the tenor and substance of the Sino-North Korean relationship. As is well known, the relationship suffered a deep dive in 2017 through to mid-2018 on the back of a number of North Korean missile and nuclear weapons tests — provocations that prompted China to publicly rebuke Pyongyang and even support sanctions against the hermit state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hong Kong&#39;s wealthy elite feel the heat from Beijing</title>
      <link>https://neasair.org/blog/2015/taiwan-elite-beijing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://neasair.org/blog/2015/taiwan-elite-beijing/</guid>
      <description>Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s wealthy elite feel the heat from Beijing The Australian October 5, 2015
https://www.theaustralian.com.au/business/business-spectator/news-story/hong-kongs-wealthy-elite-feel-the-heat-from-beijing/beed3f42254d374b54185b2190cdafe6
Debate is continuing in China about an article published over a week ago titled Don&amp;rsquo;t let Li Ka-shing run. Produced by the Outlook Think Tank, a subsidiary of the state mouthpiece Xinhua, the article was seen to reflect official angst at Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s formerly favoured &amp;lsquo;superman&amp;rsquo; entrepreneur and Asia&amp;rsquo;s richest man.
Its main criticism was directed at Li&amp;rsquo;s decision to sell-off prime Chinese assets when anxieties about the economy are growing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
