<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Main page on North East Asia Security and International Relations</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Main page on North East Asia Security and International Relations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 21:14:10 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>075 Type’s 30,000 tons is enough, because China has two ‘outdated’ aircraft carriers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/30000-tons-is-enough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/30000-tons-is-enough/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 19, 2019
075三万吨足够了 因为中国有2艘“落后”航母
Fenghuang Jul 8, 2019
https://mil.ifeng.com/c/7o8UAju0Ggq
Fenghuang-online Military Affairs / Fenghuang-online Military Affairs Editorial
 075三万吨足够了 因为中国有2艘“落后”航母
 Subsequent to the recent appearance on military blogs of the Type 075 Amphibious Assault Ship [more commonly known as the Type 075 landing helicopter dock], much conjecture has again emerged in relation to the “small flat platform/deck” that is second in size only to that of an aircraft carrier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Nuclear Umbrella won&#39;t make North Korea Abandon Nuclear Weapons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/north-korea-wont-abandon-nukes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/north-korea-wont-abandon-nukes/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 19, 2019
中国向朝鲜提供核保护劝其弃核不现实
Global Times (Huanqiu)
Nov 13, 2013
http://mil.huanqiu.com/paper/2013-11/4558761.html?agt=15422
Full title: It is not Realistic for China to Provide North Korea with a Nuclear Umbrella in order to Persuade it to Abandon Nuclear Weapons
Zhang Liangui 张琏瑰 - Institute for International Strategic Studies of the Central Party School of the Communist Party of China 中共中央黨校國際戰略研究所
 中国向朝鲜提供核保护劝其弃核不现实
 Note This article was written in 2013. However, it outlines the unique perspective on the issue of nuclearisation on the Korean peninsula of an informed and influential Chinese thinker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: If American arms sales go too far they will endanger Taiwan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/american-arms-sales-may-endanger-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/american-arms-sales-may-endanger-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 19, 2019
社评：美对台军售，走过头就是台湾之危
Global Times July 9, 2019
http://baijiahao.baidu.com/s?id=1638561132431613159&amp;amp;wfr=spider&amp;amp;for=pc
America’s Department of Defence announced on Monday that it had approved the sale of military equipment worth approximately 2.2 billion American dollars to Taiwan. The deal includes 108 M1a2T Abraham tanks and 250 FIM-92 Stinger Man-Portable Air Defence Systems. Many American media reports pointed out that the sale occurred in the backdrop of the ongoing trade war between America and China.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Korean War and China’s Strategic Decisions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/korean-war-china-strategic-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/korean-war-china-strategic-decisions/</guid>
      <description>朝顯戰爭與中國的決策
Shen Zhihua 沈志華
Notes from Shen Zhihua&amp;rsquo;s presentation, delivered at the Yonsei Institute of Sinology (Seoul), Jun 19, 2019
Periodization of the Korean war (in terms of shifts in China’s strategic aims):
 朝顯戰爭與中國的決策
   Engaging in military action to pursue a settlement - October 1950 to December 1950
  Fighting without negotiation: Pushing the American military back to the Pacific Ocean - January 1951 to May 1951.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-China sentiments are spreading in Pyongyang</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/pyongyang-anti-china-sentiment-spreading/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/pyongyang-anti-china-sentiment-spreading/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 19, 2019
평양시민들 사이에 반중 분위기 확산
RFA, Aug. 22, 2018
https://www.rfa.org/korean/in_focus/nk_nuclear_talks/antichina-08222018102647.html
Anchor:
Leading up to the 70th anniversary of the political leadership of the Worker’s Party of Korea’s (WPK), a rumour has spread in Pynogyang that China’s Chairman Xi Jinping could visit North Korea. However, a source has indicated that anti-China sentiments have grown among Pyongyang intellectuals as well as among the city’s residents.
 평양시민들 사이에 반중 분위기 확산</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From the Heisei to the Reiwa era - the Self Defence Force and National Security of a Changing Japan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/the-sdf-and-national-security-of-a-changing-japan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/the-sdf-and-national-security-of-a-changing-japan/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 19, 2019
平成から令和へ。変わる日本の自衛隊と安全保障
Asahi May 22, 2019
https://webronza.asahi.com/politics/articles/2019052200004.html
Gen Nakatani, Former Minister of Defence, on the transformation of the JSDF (Japanese Self Defence Force) and national security*, and the current state of Japan.
Gen Nakatani - Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) Member of the House of Representatives, Former Minister of Defence
 平成から令和へ。変わる日本の自衛隊と安全保障
 Introduction The Reiwa period has begun. With America’s transformation and the rise of China’s military etc, the international environment around Japan is undergoing a transformation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North Korea, which is calling for self-rejuvination, is preparing itself for the global economy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/north-korea-preparing-for-global-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/north-korea-preparing-for-global-economy/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 13, 2019
자력갱생 외치는 북한, 글로벌경제 대비
Yonhap News TV
June 8, 2019
http://www.yonhapnewstv.co.kr/MYH20190607019400038/?did=1825m
(Anchor) Although North Korea is calling for economic construction through self-rejunivation*, internally, Pyongyang is emphasising the concept of globalisation and is attempting to transition its economy.
 자력갱생 외치는 북한, 글로벌경제 대비
 Kim Jung-un, chairman of North Korea’s state affairs commission, has personally come out and tried to raise awareness about intellectual property rights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>President Moon warns Japan: ‘A necessary response when Korean companies are harmed’</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/moon-warns-japan-when-korean-companies-harmed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/moon-warns-japan-when-korean-companies-harmed/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 13, 2019
문 대통령 “한국기업 피해 땐 필요한 대응” 일본에 경고
Hani.co.kr, July 8, 2019
http://www.hani.co.kr/arti/politics/bluehouse/900913.html#csidx6183caecd1c96ed8c3be1b3174e758f
In response to restrictions on the export of core materials for semi-conductors and display devises being led by Japan’s Prime Minister Shinzo Abe, President Moon Jae-in on Jul 8 warned that ‘the vicious cycle of response and recrimination is definitely not what either nation wants,’ yet ‘if damage to Korean companies actually occurs, as the representative government we will have to respond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Abe administration&#39;s diplomatic achievements are being called into question [excerpt]</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/abe-administration-achievements-called-into-question/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/abe-administration-achievements-called-into-question/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 13, 2019
北方領土、拉致解決進まず＝日中改善も公船侵入続く－問われる安倍政権【19参院選】
Jiji, July 2, 2019
https://www.jiji.com/jc/article?k=2019070200701&amp;amp;g=pol
Full title: No progress in resolving the Northern Territories / kidnapping [disputes] = In spite of improvements in Sino-Japanese relations, Chinese public vessels continuously encroach in Japanese waters - Abe’s administration is being called into question (19 House of Councillors election)
 北方領土、拉致解決進まず＝日中改善も公船侵入続く－問われる安倍政権【19参院選】
 In the Liberal Democratic Party’s (LDP) campaign promises during the upper house elections, diplomacy was thrust to the forefront.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘The security treaty between the United States and Japan is unfair’ is an old argument</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/us-japan-security-treaty-an-old-argument/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2019/us-japan-security-treaty-an-old-argument/</guid>
      <description>Updated: Jul 13, 2019
「日米安保は不公平」は、今に始まった議論ではない
Asabi Shimbun Globe
July 7, 2019
https://globe.asahi.com/article/12508614
Since it was reported that President Trump talked about ‘tearing up’ the Japan-U.S. security treaty, there has been ongoing uncertainty has about what will become of the Japan-U.S. alliance. Although it doesn’t appear to be the case that this was directly touched upon in the leaders’ meeting, it is clear that a conflict of interests exists. In response to the American president’s insistence that ‘Japan does not have an obligation to defend America - a one-sided treaty is unfair,’ Japan responded by noting that ‘Japan’s has taken on an appropriate burden in matters such as providing financial support for U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 14:09:28 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>NEASAIR provides Anglophone readers interested in security and international relations in North East Asia with a window into the unique perspectives, insights and foci of Chinese, Japanese and Korean language media and analyses.
NEASAIR is different. It&amp;rsquo;s primary aim is to give Anglophone readers interested in security and international relations in North East Asia a window into the unique perspectives, insights and foci that can be found in Chinese, Japanese and Korean language media and analyses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
